#Encodergasm Presents
～
Hey, Spike!
（ジェット）おい スパイク
It's ready!
（ジェット）あがったぞ
（スパイク）こっちもあがりだ
I'm just about done myself.  What's cooking?
メニューは？
特製チンジャオロース
Special "beef with bell peppers."
Asimov Solensan.  This is our next target.
（ジェット）
アシモフ･ソーレンサン
こいつが次の賞金首だ
Hey, Jet...
ジェットさんよ
アステロイド一帯を仕切る
組織の幹部なんだがな
He's a high-end of the syndicate that deals all around the asteroids.
About this beef with bell peppers...
（スパイク）
チンジャオロースっつったよな
The guy's name is Asimov Solensan.  Weren't you listening to me?!
アシモフ･ソーレンサンだよ
何 聞いてんだ
（スパイク）肉のない
チンジャオロースなんてのは―
You DON'T call a meatless "beef with bell peppers"...
..."beef with bell peppers," do you?
チンジャオロースとは
言わねんじゃねえのかな
Yes, you do.
いや 言うね
言わねえよ
No, you don't!
You do when you're broke!
金がないときは言うんだよ
この間の賞金 100万ウーロンは
どこいったんだよ
What happened to the million woolongs we got as bounty from that last guy?!
The repair bill for the plane you wrecked...
お前が壊した機体の修理と―
...and the repair bill for the shop you trashed...
お前が壊した店の修理と―
お前が
ケガさせた警官の治療費で―
...and the medical bill of the cop you injured...
パーだ！
KILLED ALL THE DOUGH!
Three days ago, there was a shootout between his group and an enemy syndicate.
３日前 こいつの組織と―
敵対する組織との
抗争があったんだが―
He killed his own men and took off.
こいつは仲間を殺して
とんずらしやがった
やつはティワナの女の所に
逃げ込んだらしい
They say he's hiding with his woman in Tijuana.
（スパイク）
あんな所 雑魚の行く所だよ
That's a place for nobodies to go.
雑魚の割に賞金は250万だ
Despite being a nobody, he's worth 2.5 million.
（スパイク）乗らねえな
Don't feel like it.
ティワナか　あそこの牛は―
Tijuana...  The beef there...
うまいわな
...is REALLY tasty.
Attention, please.  We will soon arrive at the gate.
We look forward to serving you again.
（ゲートアナウンス）
間もなくゲートに到着いたします
またのご利用を
お待ちしております
Please line up single file at the tollbooth after clearing the gate.
ゲートを通過しましたら
料金所に１列でお並びください
クレジットセンサーを―
Please pass by after switching the credit sensors to debit mode.
引き落としモードにして
通過してください
I'll head over after hitting the cops for clues.
（ジェット）とりあえず こっちは
警察筋にあたってから行く
Then I'll try seeing old man Bull.
（スパイク）じゃあこっちは
ブルのおっさん所でも
行ってみるわ
Can you trust that old guy?
（ジェット）
当てになんのかねえ あのおやじ
（スパイクの
Such an easygoing song.
のんきな曲だぜ
THIEF!
（男性）泥棒！
This again?  God damn son of a bitch!
（アントニオ）
まただ 畜生 この野郎
Man, you're totally ripping me off, but do ya realize...
お前らそうやって俺のこと
カモにしてっけどな
今 こうやって
ここに住んでられるってのも―
...the reason you can live here is because...
...I dug that gate with all my might, ya hear?
俺が一生懸命
ゲート 掘ったおかげなんだぞ
This again.  You always say that when you lose.
（カルロス）
おめえは負けると いっつもそれだ
We all dug the gate together, remember?
ゲートは俺たち みんなで
掘ったんだろう
（ジョビン）掘ったな
死に物狂いで掘ったな
That we did.  We dug like there was no tomorrow...
God damn idiot son of a bitch!
ばか野郎 この野郎　うん？
Gimme a beer.
（アシモフ）ビールをくれ
And I'll have a Bloody Mary.
（カテリーナ）
私はブラッディマリーを
ひと吹きお願い
I got vodka, but unfortunately I'm out of tomato juice.
ウオッカはあるが あいにく
トマトジュースを切らしててね
奥に１缶くらい
あるんじゃないか？
I'm sure there's one can in the back room...
見てみよう
I'll take a look.
レッド･アイの最上級品だ
Top-notch "red-eye."
売人なら分かるだろ
You'd know, as a buyer, right?
Can it be..."BLOODY-EYE"?
まさか… ブラッディ･アイ！
（３人）おお
Prove to me that it's the real thing.
本物かどうか 見せてもらおうか
（心臓の鼓動）
（アシモフ）ううう…！
Keep those eyes open!
よーく見ておくんだな
うおっ…
いやー
（アシモフ）ふっ！
うはあ… うお…
This is dandy, but you got anything to eat?
これもいいけど
なんか食いもんねえの？
はあー あっそ
I see...
The red-eyed coyote will appear at the north end of town.
（ブル）北の街はずれに
赤い目のコヨーテは現れる
That is what I see.
そう出ている
A red-eyed coyote, huh...
（スパイク）赤い目のコヨーテね
You, "Swimming Bird."
（ブル）泳ぐ鳥よ
（スパイク）うん？
You shall meet a woman.
お前は女に出会う
You shall be targeted by that woman...
お前は女に狙われる
そして―
And then... death.
死ぬ
Again.  I see.
またかよ
"Again"?
また？
（スパイク）
俺は１回 死んでるんだよ
I've already died once.  Got killed by a woman.
女に殺されてね
You take women too lightly.
（ブル）
お前は女を甘く見ておる
（スパイク）お邪魔さん
Catch you later.
ワカン･タンカの恵みあれ
May he be blessed by Wakantanka.
Presidente?  I'll have a glass on the house.
（ジェット）プレシデンテか
一杯おごってもらうぜ
Damn.  Asimov sure lost his head.
（ギャングＡ）
ったく アシモフの野郎
キレまくってんぜ
No shit.  We gotta do something before the cops start moving.
（ギャングＢ）やっべえな
サツが動き出す前に
何とかしねえと
Ya wanna leave it up to the cops?
（ギャングＡ）
いっそサツに任せるか？
He IS using those eye drops.  There's no way we can win.
やつは例の目薬 使ってんだ
かなわねえ
I'm tellin' ya, we got nothin' if we don't get that "BLOODY-EYE" back.
だから そのブラッディ･アイを
取り返さねえと―
話になんねんだろうが
But, man!
だってよお
Hey.
（ジェット）よう
Can you give me the specifics?
詳しく聞きたいねえ
Man, I'm hungry...
腹減ったなあ
（スパイク）うん？
You, too?
（スパイク）お前もかよ
（スパイクの
（荒い息）
水 流したほうがいいっすよ
It's better to leave the water running.
Or it'll clog.
（スパイク）詰まるから
（スパイクの
（カテリーナ）あっ
（スパイク）うわ
（スパイク）おっと
Oh, I'm sorry!
（カテリーナ）
あっ ごめんなさい
ありがとう
Thank you...
あら？
Um...
あの…
すいません
...I'f soffy.
Ew!  I don't want that anymore!  You can have it!
嫌！ もういらない あげるわよ
Lukfy!
ラッキー
（スパイク）
ハハ いやあ 失敬失敬
I'm really sorry, honest.
おなかと背中が
くっつきそうだったもんで
Felt like my stomach was going to be glued to my back.
（カテリーナ）まあ　アッハハハ
（スパイク）ハハハハ
Nice fighter.
（カテリーナ）いい機体ね
（スパイク）古い型さ
It's an old model.
10年来の相棒だ
She's been with me for over ten years.
Looks like you've gotten a lot of use out of it.
随分 ムチャやってるみたい
あちこち旅してるからなあ
I travel around a lot.
本当は旅芸人なんだ
I'm actually a wandering performer.
フフッ　冗談か本気か
分からない人ね
I can't tell if you're for real or just joking.
よく言われるよ
A lot of people say that about me.
（カテリーナ）火星にも行った？
Been to Mars yet?
（スパイク）火星生まれだ
I was born on Mars.
（カテリーナ）
あそこは何でもあるんでしょう
They have everything there.
こんな所と違って―
Unlike here, Mars has lots of people, lots of things...
いろんな人がいて
いろんな物があって―
幸せに暮らしてるって
They must live happily there.
（スパイク）
金があるやつだけさ
Only the rich.
じゃあ きっと幸せになれるわ
Then I'm sure we'll be happy there.
（スパイク）
火星へ逃げるつもりか？
You planning on escaping to Mars?
Running away... but how far can you go?
（スパイク）逃げ回っても
どこまで行けるかな
Who are you?
（カテリーナ）誰なの？
An old-fashioned cowboy.
時代遅れのカウボーイさ
A bounty hunter?
賞金稼ぎね
Good call.
ご名答
You're not going to catch us?
捕まえないの？
Your buddy seems to be pretty ill.
（スパイク）あんたの連れは
体を かなりやられてる
I don't deal with weakened nobodies.
弱ってる雑魚は相手にしないんだ
Wise decision.
（カテリーナ）それが利口だわ
YOU are the nobody!
雑魚はお前だ
（アシモフ）うーん ああ
Asimov!  That's enough!
アシモフ もう十分よ
（スパイク）うっ ああ…
アディオス カウボーイ
Adios, cowboy.
Why did you stop me?
（アシモフ）なぜ止めた？
（カテリーナ）えっ？
I coulda killed him in one second.
あいつの息を止めるなんざ
１秒でできた
You're tired.  If you do this anymore...
（カテリーナ）あんた疲れてるわ
これ以上…
He was young and attractive.
（アシモフ）
若くて いい男だったな
I was waiting so long for you to come pick me up.
私 あんたが迎えに来てくれるの
ずっと待ってた
I can finally escape the low life I've had here.
やっと ここの暮らしから
抜け出せるんじゃない
I can finally live happily on Mars...
火星で幸せに暮らせるのよ
A nap.  How peaceful.
昼寝とは優雅だな
I had a good dream.
いい夢見たぜ
That's great.
（ジェット）ああ それは結構
Then you can see the rest of that dream on the Bebop.
じゃあ その続きでも
ビバップに戻ってゆっくり見てくれ
I'm giving up on this one.
今回は俺も諦めた
It's impossible to catch him.
やつを捕まえるのは無理だ
There's no way we can win.
かなうわけないわな
アシモフは組織を逃げ出すときに
ある物を持ち出したんだ
When Asimov left his syndicate, he snuck something out with him.
The top-end stuff of all the illegal eye drops that the syndicate makes.
組織の資金源となってた―
非合法目薬ん中でも
飛び切りの上物だ
He took off with all of the drops, so the group is in a mess.
そいつを全部 持って
逃げたもんだから 連中は大騒ぎよ
捕まえようにも
死人ばっか増えちまう
They want to catch him, but all they get back are corpses.
アシモフは使ってるからよ
その目薬
Because Asimov is using it...
The eye drops known as "BLOODY-EYE."
ブラッディ･アイをな
They're planning on going to Mars.
やつらは火星に行くつもりだぜ
Mars?
（ジェット）火星？
But before that, they'll sell this off.
その前に こいつを売りさばく
Hmm?  That's...
（ジェット）うん？ それは…
I grabbed it from his breast pocket.
（スパイク）
やつの懐から頂戴した
You... met him?
（ジェット）お前 会ったのか
A nightmare.
悪い夢さ
ふっ やられたな
He got you?
The red-eyed coyote will supposedly appear at the north end of town.
赤い目のコヨーテは
北の街はずれに現れるそうだ
（パトカーのサイレン）
（アシモフ）ん？
（アシモフ）はあ
This again?  God damn son of a bitch!
（アントニオ）
またかよ 畜生この野郎
Man, you're totally rippin' me off, but do ya realize the reason you can eat well...
お前ら そうやって俺のこと
カモにしてっけどな
この辺りの店で
うまいもん食えるのも―
...around here is because I cultivated the land with my buddies, ya hear?
俺が仲間と一緒に
この土地 耕したおかげなんだぞ
Yeah, and that's us.
そりゃ俺たちだっつうの
That we did...
耕したな　死に物狂いで種まいた
We planted seeds like there was no tomorrow...
You were always planting "seeds" of a different kind, though!
おめえは別の種まいてたもんさな
（アントニオ）おっ？
You have any Bloody Marys?
ブラッディマリーはあるか？
I only got beer.
（スパイク）ビールしかないな
I've got tomato juice.
（アシモフ）
トマトジュースならある
How much?
（スパイク）いくらだ？
300,000 woolongs.  I got 50 packs.
（アシモフ）30万ウーロンだ
50袋ある
15 million woolongs, eh?
（スパイク）1500万ウーロンか
急いでる
I'm in a hurry.  I'll find others if you don't want it.
駄目なら他をあたる
Show me.
（スパイク）見せてくれ
Lookin' for this?
これかい？
Hey, do you know what YOU are worth?
あんた自分の値段 知ってるか？
何？
What?
Only 2.5 million woolongs.
たったの250万ウーロンだぜ
You're such a cheap guy.
安い男だな
Long time no see.
ご無沙汰
（アシモフ）
いつから売人になった？
Since when are you a buyer?  Did you give up on bounty hunting?
賞金稼ぎは諦めたか
No thrill in cheap bounties.
安い賞金首じゃ
張り合いなくてね
Looks like you do better as a thief.
お前は盗っ人が向いてるようだな
返してもらおう
Give it back.
Sure I will.
返すとも　あんたには借りがある
I owe you one!
うわっ！　うっ…
目に頼り過ぎなんだよ
You trust your eyes too much!  You're not a chameleon!
カメレオンじゃねえんだ
あちこち見えねえのさ
You can't see everywhere all at once!
あっ あう…
ぐあっ
（カテリーナ）あっ？
（アシモフ）うっ 行くぞ
Let's go!
That way!
（ギャングＣ）あっちだー
That way!  That way!
あっちだ あっち　うわあっ
何だ てめえ　うわっ
What the hell are you?!
Don't move!
（カテリーナ）動かないで！
（男性）おお…
All right, stay still!
（カテリーナ）いい？
そのまま じっとしてるのよ
（カテリーナ）あっ…
IDIOT!
ばか野郎！
We're doomed if these break!  Be more careful!
こいつが潰れたら終わりなんだ
気をつけろ
（スパイク）
このっ しつけえんだっつうの
（一同）うわーっ
いやー
ふん お待たせ
Sorry to keep you waiting.
おせえぞ ジェット！
You're late, Jet!
Oh...
いっけね
...shit!
（アシモフ）うう… うう…
（カテリーナ）アシモフ
Asimov.
やめて！
もう これ以上 ムチャよ
Stop!  Doing any more is insane!  Don't do it!
駄目！
（アシモフ）うわっ
We can't run anymore...
もう逃げきれないわ
逃げきれやしない
There's no way we can get away...
（スパイク）はっ！
Adios...
アディオス
Hey, Spike, it's ready!
おい スパイク あがったぞ
（ジェット）あがったぞ
It's ready.
（スパイク）メニューは？
What's cooking?
特製チンジャオロースだ
Special "beef with bell peppers."
Aishiteta to nageku niwa
Too much time has passed by...
...to lament that we were deeply in love.
Amarinimo toki wa sugite shimatta
The wind keeps blowing, while my heart...
Mada kokoro no hokorobi wo
...cannot heal all the tears in it.
lyasenu mama kaze ga fuiteru
Someone, cry for me with parched eyes.
Kawaita hitomi de dareka naite kure
The real folk blues.
The real folk blues
I only want to know what true sadness is.
Honto no kanashimi ga shiritai dake
Sitting in muddy water...
Doro no kawa ni tsukatta
...isn't such a bad life...
Jinsei mo waruku wa nai
...if it ends after the first time...
Ichido kiri de owaru nara
～
Well, and so this program is finally under way.
（スパイク）まあ そういうわけで
ようやく始まった この番組
（ジェット）
こりゃ どういうわけだよ
What's the meaning of all this?
（スパイク）来週は思い切って
ファミリーアニメに大変身だ
Next week, we're completely changing gears to show an anime for all ages.
Was it that kind of a story?
（ジェット）そんな話だっけか？
（スパイク）
愉快な動物たちが大暴れ
Cheerful animals wreak havoc all over!
WHAT?!
（ジェット）何？
But Dr.  Doolittle WON'T be making an appearance.
（スパイク）と言っても
ムツゴロウさんは出てこないぞ
動物好きの子供から
お年寄りまで…
From little kids to the elderly, if you love animals...
Hey, hold on now, Spike!
（ジェット）
おい ちょっと待てよ スパイク
（スパイク）
みんな そろって見てくれよ
Everyone gather around and watch the show!
（ジェット）
そんなこと言って本当 大丈夫か？
Is it all right to say stuff like that?!
I'm not responsible for anything!
俺 知らねえぞ
（スパイク）
でも ここで一つ
お願いがあるんだ
But there is one favor to ask right now.
良い子のみんなは
テレビから離れて見てくれ
Good little kids should sit far from the TV when watching the show.
Come on...
（ジェット）お前なあ
（スパイク）１キロぐらいな
Stand back about a kilometer.
That's TOO far.
（ジェット）離れすぎだよ
（スパイク）800メートル？
800 meters then?